SAI TEJA BOORGU

☐ 513-837-5826 | Mail boorgusaiteja@gmail.com | in LinkedIn | ☐ GitHub

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Software Development Engineer with master's in computer science and 4+ years of experience at companies. Looking for a challenging role in a reputable organization to utilize my technical, database, and management skills for the growth of the organization as well as to enhance my knowledge about new and emerging trends in the IT sector.

EDUCATION

Master of Engineering in Computer Science

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio

Aug 2021- Dec 2022

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering

Malla Reddy Institute of Technology, Hyderabad, Telangana, India

Aug 2016 - May 2020

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

Skills:

Expert: Java, Python, JavaScript, Git version control, Scala, HTML, React, SQL and Dynamo DB Advanced: Rust, TypeScript, Node.js, Angular, Object-oriented design, Software/hardware int

Amazon Web Services: Aws Cloud Formation, Amazon CloudWatch Metrics, Amazon EC2, API Gateway, Lambdas, Amazon S3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer, Amazon Web Services, Seattle, Washington

Aug 2022 – Present

- **Roles:**
 - Experience with AWS S3 services creating buckets, configuring buckets with permissions, logging, versioning, and tagging.
 - Designed, developed, and tested an intelligent, thoughtful, and continuously running sweeper program to reduce the amount of data stored in Amazon S3.
 - Managing cloud services, cloud Watch metrics and DynamoDB tables.
 - Analysis of Amazon's storage solutions: S3, S3 Standard IA, S3 Reduced Redundancy to further drastically. reduce the team's costs.
 - Work in an agile environment to deliver high-quality software.
 - Build distributed storage, index, and query systems that are scalable, fault-tolerant, low cost, and easy to manage/use.
 - Involved in unit testing of various modules by generating test cases using Junit, Mockito, Google Guice Module Testing and Karma.
 - Designed and Developed the Automation Testing Framework using Java, TestNG, Scala Test.
 - Used Log4j for logging and debugging and used JUnit extensively for testing.

Trainee Software Engineer, Eidiko System Integrators Private Limited, Hyderabad, India Roles:

Feb 2020 – Jul 2021

- Designed and developed the application using Agile Scrum methodology by breaking down the project to several sprints.
- Used Hibernate annotations for Object Relational Mapping (ORM) with Oracle database.
- Developed the persistence layer (DAO) and the presentation layer (controllers) and used J2EE design patterns like Model View Controller, Data Access Object, and Business Delegate, etc.
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) of the application like Requirement gathering, Design, Analysis, Code development and estimating the timeline for the stories and project.
- Worked on GIT as a version control. Utilized NPM scripts for build and test environments in a Node.js application.
- Expertise worked on continuous build integration (CI/CD) tools Jenkins.
- Involved in the unit testing by writing the test cases and test suites with the help of JUNIT.
- Implemented RESTful web services which produces both XML and JSON files to perform tasks, RESTful web service using Jersey for JAX-RS implementation, which leveraged both web & mobile applications.
- Design and develop and test HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery and Angular.js that meets accessibility and web browser standards for website.

Python Developer, VN Career Solutions, Hyderabad, India

May 2019 – July 2019

Project: Analysis of Applicants Count in Financial Services

Forecasting cases of loans aggregated at Country level. An important starting point in the forecasting process is the re-assessment of the economic climate in individual countries and the world economy. Here, a combination of model-based analyses and statistical indicator models play an important role in "setting the scene" at the start of each projection round. The basic motive of my project is forecasting daily cases of loans aggregated at the Country level keeping in consideration the major Indian festivals.

- Identifying the threats in the account by manual reading of the entire timeline of the account holders.
- I have done so many analyses like Twitter data analysis, Pokémon go data analysis using different methods in data science
- Collected real time data.
- Analyzed real time problems.
- Prepared an analysis document.

Environment: Kaggle, Support vector machines experts for time series forecasting.

Data Analyst, Lasya Infotech, Hyderabad, India

July 2018 - May 2019

Project: Scalable Framework for Stylometric Analysis Query Processing

The emphasis was on classifying Stylometry is the statistical analyses of variations in the author's literary style. The technique has been used in many linguistic analysis applications, such as, author profiling, authorship identification, and authorship verification.

- Perform some analysis whether the device is capturing the correct data.
- Prepare a Design documentation on Project Analysis.
- Developed bulk digital benefit purchase and management functionality which is now publicly known as buy for others feature on amazon retail website.
- Designed and executed high scale database migration from SQL to NoSQL database for live digital gifting application with zero downtime.